INTEGRATED HR SYSTEMS CONSULTANT & SR. PROJECT MANAGER

Executive Summary

A seasoned HR professional with strong operational, technical, and process improvement expertise. Regularly recognized by management and stakeholders for a consultative approach and solutions orientated thinking to problem solving. Experience with large, complex global project implementations with a proven track record to implement solutions that focus on the requirements of key stakeholders while balancing the needs of corporate objectives and directives.

Core Qualifications

- HR Expertise
- Operational Strengths
- Leadership Skills
- HR Systems & Technology
- Project Management
- Building Trust
- Compensation Plan Design & Management
- Process Improvement
- Credibility
- Benefit Plan Design & Administration
- Shared Services
- Teamwork
- HR Business Partner Support & Modeling
- Centers of Excellence
- Collaboration Oracle, Taleo, PeopleSoft, ADP, Ultipro, NuView, Kronos, Ceridian
- Software Expertise
- Excel, Access, Word, Project, PowerPoint, Crystal Reports, SharePoint, Visio

Professional Experience

Integrated HR Systems Consultant & Sr. Project Manager Jan 2011 to Current Temple University $i\frac{1}{4}$ PA , State

- A global professional services, advertising, and technology branding company with 14,000 employees worldwide.
- Responsible for all PM related activities in support of compensation, performance management, competency frameworks, development planning, and learning/training applications.
- Implemented a prioritization process with a single central function to streamline the pipeline of requests across all HR related functions globally which facilitated engagement activities between key business stakeholders and the IT organization.
- Served as the lead project manager for the implementation of a new learning management system which included ecommerce functionality, employee self-directed learning activities, a content curation strategy, and mobile access.
- Created a standardized project management methodology and dashboard reporting metrics for use as a roadmap for all internal projects.

Consultant - Global Compensation Manager Jan 2010 to Jan 2011

Temple University il/4 Philadelphia, PA

- A leading owner and operator of global communications sites for the wireless and broadcast industries.
- Managed the design and administration of global compensation programs including base pay and performance incentives.
- Oversaw the annual compensation planning process for all country locations.
- Provided forecasting and modeling methodologies for the annual equity grant process.

Consultant Project Manager Jan 2009 to Jan 2010

Temple University i $^{1}\!/_{4}$ Ambler , PA

- A leading manufacturer of medical devices, diagnostic imaging, and pharmaceuticals with over 40,000 employees worldwide.
- Managed 15 separate project teams made up of key HR and business leaders to create a new global compensation job family hierarchy across the organization.
- Partnered with global Compensation Center of Excellence (COE) Managers to identify market survey benchmark matches based on internal
 job content.
- Regions included USA, Canada, Latin America, Europe and Asia Pacific.
- Created global job titling matrices by job family which recognized cultural differences within each region/country.
- Worked closely with global business leaders to identify various scope factors (such as plant size, revenue, work complexity, autonomy, impact, scope, experience level, etc.), which were used to create a new job evaluation tool for grade level assignments.

Director Jan 2008 to Jan 2009

Chewy i1/4 Boston, MA

- A total aviation solution with a range of services and capabilities, including aircraft charter and aircraft management, to fulfill the complete spectrum of private aviation needs.
- HR Systems, Compensation, & Benefits.
- Primary objective was to design and implement a competitive and comprehensive benefits & compensation package to assist employees in

- maintaining a healthy lifestyle, achieving financial security and address work and family needs.
- Designed and built an on-line Benefits Portal using SharePoint for employees and HR team members to gain 24x7 access to important benefits information, forms, life event assistance, and enrollment information.
- As a result of several mergers and acquisitions, successfully coordinated the transition of (5) separate 401k plans into a single company sponsored plan.

Head of HR Systems & Compensation Jan 2007 to Jan 2008 Temple University $i^{1}/4$ Harrisburg , PA

- An award winning general contracting and construction management firm.
- Served as the lead project manager to implement a new HR Information System which included employee and manager self-service capabilities resulting in significant efficiency improvements across multiple HR transactional processes as well as new metric report methodologies.
- Collaborated with the HR Business Partner and Finance Teams to create a new compensation plan that produced the optimal balance of
 cost, risk and reward to reflect the business strategy while maintaining competitiveness.

Director Jan 2005 to Jan 2007 Fisery, Inc. il/4 Parsippany, NJ

- A leading provider of integrated vehicle and driver programs in North America HR Systems, Payroll, Compensation, & Benefits.
- Responsible for the creation of a HR Technology Strategy to leverage the use of improved Human Resource Information System tools to create a more efficient, integrated solution that covered multiple HR functions.
- Implemented a new comprehensive Wellness program incorporating on-line tools and programs designed to be customized by employee specific needs.
- Managed the strategic implementation of both direct and indirect reward and recognition programs within the organization.
- These included benefits, base compensation, bonus incentives, recognition, and career growth opportunities.

Director Jan 2003 to Jan 2005

World Travel Holdings i1/4 City, STATE

- One of the largest online and offline leisure travel companies serving consumers through a portfolio of owned and licensed brands.
- HR Systems, Compensation, & Benefits.
- Managed a benefit Request for Proposal (RFP) process, resulting in the implementation of new medical, dental, and disability programs that saved \$1,000,000 in renewal costs and over \$400,000 in actual budgeted costs.
- Implemented a new HR Business Partner model, which transformed the HR department from a transactional-based philosophy to one that focused on aligning its services, programs, and practices with the company's business and financial strategies.
- Led a HR project team to introduce and communicate the concept of performance management into the organization.
- This included the development of a new performance appraisal process, individual development plans, and the setting of "SMART" objectives that were linked to corporate strategies.
- The net result was a 94% success rate of on-time performance appraisals during the initial focal review period.

Systems Project Manager Jan 2000 to Jan 2003

Workscape i1/4 City, STATE

- A leading provider of Internet-based Human Capital solutions and Human Resources self-service applications.
- Partnered with clients to assess their HR needs specifically related to benefits, compensation, 401k/pension, and HRIS administration.
- Recommended application deployment strategies and provided project management implementation support.
- Project Management responsibilities include estimation, monitoring, escalations, troubleshooting, issues identification, facilitation, and resolution, inquiry tracking, customer reporting, and trend identification.

Director Jan 1997 to Jan 2000

NE Restaurant Company, Inc i1/4 City, STATE

- Regional restaurant chain with over 120 units and \$300 million in annual sales.
- HR Systems & Total Rewards Implemented a new client-server based HR/Payroll system (Ultripro) requiring the merging of data from two separate payroll systems.
- Facilitated negotiations with medical network vendors resulting in increased employee participation and utilization rates while lowering loss ratios by 15%.
- Responsible for corporate and field level benefit and compensation programs as well as the functional use of HR information systems in support of these programs.
- Successful projects included the implementation of an executive stock option plan, an executive deferred compensation plan, a competency-based career development plan, and the streamlining of all bonus incentives plans to support company objectives.

Manager - HR Jan 1987 to Jan 1997

Hills Department Stores il/4 City, STATE

• Regional discount department store chain with 154 units and \$1.8 billion in annual sales.

- Managed the administration of all compensation programs and processes including job analysis, job description development, market analysis, and the communication of such programs to line management.
- Acted as the liaison between the HR, Information Systems, and Payroll areas to coordinate the production of standard and customized system reports.
- Incorporated HR systems experience to automate the manual entry of annual performance appraisal data.

Education

Bachelors Degree , Business Administration Computer Systems Grove City College it/4 City , State Business Administration Computer Systems Skills

streamline, ADP, advertising, automate, balance, Benefits, branding, broadcast, business strategy, Ceridian, client-server, competitive, concept, construction management, content, Crystal Reports, clients, ecommerce, equity, Finance, financial, forecasting, forms, functional, HRIS, Human Resource, Human Resources, HR, imaging, Information Systems, job analysis, Kronos, Latin, Leadership Skills, market analysis, market, mergers and acquisitions, Access, Excel, PowerPoint, SharePoint, Word, Modeling, negotiations, network, Oracle, Payroll, PeopleSoft, performance appraisal, performance management, philosophy, processes, Process Improvement, Project Management, Proposal, reporting, RFP, sales, Strategy, strategic, Teamwork, trend, troubleshooting, Visio